How is your memory?
你的记忆力怎么样？
Remembering things is an important function of our brain – if we can’t recall how to do something, we can’t survive.
记忆是大脑的一项重要功能——如果我们记不起该做什么，就无法生存。
If you think about it, there is so much we have to remember – from where we left our car keys to how we walk.
仔细想想，我们需要记住的东西实在太多了——从车钥匙放在哪儿，到如何走路。
Maybe it’s no surprise that sometimes we are forgetful.
如此看来，我们偶尔健忘也就不足为奇了。
Memory allows the brain to store and retrieve information when required.
记忆能让大脑在需要时储存和调取信息。
Our short-term memory can hold a small amount of information for a short time, while our long-term memory can hold an unlimited amount of information for a long time.
我们的短时记忆可以在短时间内储存少量信息，而长时记忆则能长期储存海量信息。
Our memory is amazing, but why do we still forget things?
人类的记忆如此神奇，但我们为什么还是会忘事呢？
It’s possible we don’t always store information in our memory effectively, maybe because we are in a rush or we consider it irrelevant at the time.
我们未能有效储存信息，可能是因为当时很匆忙，或是觉得这些信息无关紧要。
When we do store information, we often make connections with other things, which helps us recall it later.
当我们储存信息时，往往会将其与其他事物建立关联，这有助于我们日后回忆。
If you don’t have these connections, then it can be easier to forget.
如果没有这些关联，信息就更容易被遗忘。
Writing for the BBC’s Science Focus magazine, Luis Villazon says “It is also possible that memories decay over time.
路易斯·维拉松在为英国广播公司《科学焦点》杂志撰稿时表示：“记忆也可能会随着时间的推移而淡化。
As they have not been revisited, their biological ‘trace’ becomes weak.”
由于长期没有被唤醒，它们的生物‘痕迹’会逐渐变弱。”
It’s true that if you don’t perform a task for a long period of time, it can be difficult to recall how to do it.
确实，一项技能如果长期不使用，我们就可能会忘记操作方法。
This could be because, just like in a computer, our memory is full, or that our short-term memory is easier to access.
这或许是因为和电脑一样，我们的记忆存储空间已满，也可能是因为短时记忆的调取更为便捷。
But sometimes even our short-term memory can let us down.
但有时候，就连我们的短时记忆也会靠不住。
Have you ever gone into a room to fetch something only to forget what you wanted when you got there?
你有没有过这样的经历：走进房间想拿某样东西，可一进门就忘了要拿什么？
This is called ‘The Doorway Effect’.
这种现象被称为“门口效应”。
Writing for the BBC Future website, psychologist Tom Stafford explains that this “occurs because we change both the physical and mental environments, moving to a different room and thinking about different things.”
心理学家汤姆·斯塔福德在为英国广播公司未来网撰稿时解释道，这种现象的发生是因为“我们的物理环境和心理状态都发生了变化——走进了另一个房间，脑子里想的事情也不一样了。”
Put simply, we are metaphorically trying to spin too many plates at the same time.
简单来说，这就好比我们同时要兼顾太多事情，顾此失彼。
So, if you have a mind like a sieve, it could be because you have too much on your mind.
因此，如果你的脑子像个筛子，总是丢三落四，可能是因为脑子里的事情太多了。
But we do need to keep our memory sharp by continually using it, especially as beyond our 50s our brains tend to shrink in volume and our memory begins to decline. That’s when we’re at more risk of getting Alzheimer’s disease.
但我们确实需要通过不断使用来保持记忆力的敏锐，尤其是在50岁以后，大脑体积会逐渐萎缩，记忆力也会开始衰退，此时我们患上阿尔茨海默病的风险也会更高。
However, as Luis Villazon says, “Forgetting is not always a bad thing!
不过，正如路易斯·维拉松所说：“遗忘并非总是坏事！
It would waste cognitive resources if we remembered every detail of the world around us.”
如果我们记住周围世界的每一个细节，那会浪费大量的认知资源。”
That’s something worth remembering!
这一点，倒是值得我们铭记于心。